# **TERRA JULY RILEY**

## Analyst, EDA Expert, Web Scraper & API Aficionado

(415) 635-9770 | Oakland, CA 94609 | terrajriley@gmail.com github.com/TerraJRiley | linkedin.com/in/terra-j-riley

#### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

While I've always had a thirst for knowledge, data science has been my one true love both for the craft & the opportunity it presents to learn about the world and the people around me. I pair my data skillset with my background in communications, psychology & economics to help clients and companies discover profitable insights from their data.

#### **SKILLS & TOOLS**

Data Visualization: Tableau, Matplotlib, Google Sheets Visualizations, Seaborn

Machine Learning: Linear & Logistic Regression, K-Nearest Neighbors, Unsupervised Clustering, Neural Networks, etc.

Languages: Python, SQL

## **RELEVANT EXPERIENCE**

## Web Scraping & APIs (Various Projects)

10/2018 - 01/2019

- Utilized Selenium, Requests and BeautifulSoup libraries to gather information from various websites, such as: Google, Craigslist, The Blizzard Forums and Seeking Alpha, both out of curiosity and for clients.
- Also learned and used the Youtube and Reddit APIs for the same purposes.

## **Youtube Toxicity (Concept Project)**

10/2018 - 11/2018

- I was curious if the youtube comment was as toxic and terrible as people said that they were. Furthermore I was curious if, should toxicity be present, if said negativity was related to the communities that creators fostered.
- At the time I got the sense that most comment sections aren't toxic, but very supportive of the creators they follow.
- Executed work with Textblob sentimizer, Youtube API, latent dirichlet allocation and natural language processing.

#### **Twitter Neural Network (Concept Project)**

03/2019

• Building and improving a neural network on twitter posts to identify hate speech.

## **General Assembly Data Science Immersive**

San Francisco, CA

Data Science Student

08/2018 - 10/2018

- Full-time immersive student with 400+ hours of instruction in analyzing data sets for insights and presenting findings using statistics, programming, data modeling and business knowledge.
- Utilized the reddit API to obtain and explore data about specific subreddit communities to analyze sexism.
- Learned the Youtube API to understand the sentiment of each channel's community[].

# **Zeterre Landscape Architecture**

San Francisco, CA

Web & Brand Designer

01/2018 - 07/2018

- Organized guestionnaire database and provided useful insights from the data collected.
- Cleaned and organized content library and marketing databases resulting in easier use of these tools for the team.
- Worked with the owner and project leads to create multiple new websites from scratch.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Wicked Grounds Cafe

San Francisco, CA 06/2012 - 12/2017

Optimized ShopKeep system interface for increased ease of barista operation.

- Assisted manager in developing and implementing operational procedures to improve service quality.
- Opened and closed shop, which included counting and managing money.

San Francisco Citadel

Shift Lead

San Francisco, CA

House Manager
Managed, supported and educated volunteers on their duties to ensure smooth operations for the Citadel.

- The large of the first of the f
- Responsible for managing payment of Citadel staff members.

# **EDUCATION**

# City College of San Francisco

08/2013 - 06/2017

A.A. Degrees in Communications, Psychology, Economics, Social & Behavioral Science, Math & Science, Arts & Humanities